# **Zac Klammer**

x zklamm.github.io zklamm@gmail.com Corpus Christi, TX

#### **SUMMARY**

I'm an experienced front end software engineer comfortable with managing cloud services (AWS). I currently work at Prodly, where I use React to build a beautiful UI that interacts with complex relational data. Prior to working in software, I was a mechanical engineer working in the energy industry.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### **Software Engineer II,** *Prodly* ☑

Dec 2020 – present | Remote

- Developed guery builder that lets users create SOQL (Salesforce flavor of SQL) with clicks instead of code
- Designed/built ETL middleware that prepared relational data to be displayed in a tree structure UI
- Interfaced with GitHub, Bitbucket, and Azure API's to provide source control for Salesforce data migrations
- Worked daily with React hooks, Context, Node.js, Styled Components
- Implemented pre-commit git hooks that automatically executed linter and code formatter
- Regularly mentored junior team members
- Used tools like Slack and Gather to collaborate with fully remote team
- Second highest receiver of 'tacos' out of 55 employees from HeyTaco ☑, a coworker recognition app in Slack

## **Co-founder & Software Engineer,** *Maestro*

Jun 2020 – Dec 2020 | Remote

An open-source framework for rapidly deploying and iterating on serverless workflows that use AWS Step Functions

- Built easy-to-use CLI that abstracts away complex deployment logic, downloadable as an NPM package
- Created common templates for AWS Step Functions with the declarative, JSON-based Amazon States Language
- Wrote custom retry/backoff logic to ensure Lambda functions and state machines were created with proper roles
- Co-authored technical case study that explores the area of serverless orchestration, existing solutions in the problem space, and the process of creating Maestro maestro-framework.github.io

#### **Full Stack Web Developer.** *Self-Employed*

Aug 2017 – Dec 2020

Built several open-source projects using technologies such as React, Redux, Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML, and CSS

#### **Software Engineer,** Baytek International

Jan 2019 – Feb 2020

Contributed toward the development and testing of Baytek's LIMS (Laboratory Information Management System)

#### **Project Manager & Mechanical Engineer,** Southcross Energy

Mar 2014 - Aug 2017

Managed multi-million dollar projects from initiation to completion

### **TECHNOLOGIES**

Front End	Back End	Other
<ul> <li>JavaScript (ES5 &amp; ES6+)</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Node.js</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>HTTP/REST</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>React</li> </ul>	• SQL	<ul> <li>Git/GitHub</li> </ul>
<ul> <li>HTML/CSS</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Ruby</li> </ul>	• Jira
• jQuery	• C#	• CLI

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Software Engineering,** *Launch School* □

2017 - 2020 | Remote

An online school that teaches software fundamentals with a Mastery-Based Learning pedagogy launchschool.com/employers 🗈

**Bachelor of Science - Mechanical Engineering,** *Texas A&M University* 

2008 – 2013 | College Station, TX

### **ORGANIZATIONS**

### **Agape Ranch,** Respite Care Provider

2018 - 2020